With over seven years' experience in UX design and research, I design engaging and inclusive products and services that bring values to people's lives. I am passionate about solving complex problems and crafting delightful experiences that make a positive impact on people's lives.

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

Postdoctoral Researcher | Full-Time

Connections Lab, School of Interactive Arts & Technology, Simon Fraser University Aug 2022 – Current | Surrey, B.C., Canada

- Plan and conduct user research studies (e.g., interviews, diary studies, lab testing) to generate
 design insights for video-based collaborative systems;
- Design key interaction flows and develop high-fidelity and functional system prototypes (digital and physical) for planned research studies;
- Mentor graduate and undergraduate students in their research and design projects: help them iterate their research and design plan, navigate relevant resources, etc.

Graduate Research Assistant

GroupLens Lab, Computer Science & Engineering, University of Minnesota Aug 2017 – Aug 2022 | Minneapolis, MN, U.S.

- Planned and conducted both quantitative (e.g., experiment, survey, log analysis) and qualitative (e.g., interview, participatory design, field study) research studies to generate design directives for various systems that can better support people's activities and needs;
- Designed and developed high-fidelity and functional system prototypes to facilitate research, from interactive visualizations, tablet-based AR systems, to smart home devices;
- Ran moderated and unmoderated research studies (e.g., usability testing, field deployment) to evaluate and gather feedback on system prototypes and form new design requirements;
- Closely worked with relevant stakeholders and community partners during the research and design process, through regular status updates, visits, and workshops;
- Mentored undergraduate students in their directed and capstone projects, guiding them through various phases of the project, and achieving their professional goals.

Research Intern | Full-Time

EPIC Research Group, Microsoft Research Jun 2021 – Aug 2021 | Remote, U.S.

- Led a survey analysis to understand people's experience and workflows with multiple devices when working from home;
- Created a design framework based on the survey insights to inform designers and researchers on designing multi-device user experiences;
- Presented the framework to other design and research initiatives in the team and worked with them to help them adopt the framework.

User Experience Specialist III | Full-Time

LexisNexis

Nov 2016 - Jul 2017 | Shanghai, China

- Lead designer for cross-platform legal products (web, Windows, MacOS, Android, iOS) from user research, ideation, design, testing to feature releases;
- Closely worked with product managers and engineers in an agile environment through the product cycle, and facilitated the communications between the product and engineering teams.

Interaction Designer | Full-Time

IA Collaborative

Sept 2015 – Jun 2016 | Chicago, IL, U.S.

- Designed user experiences and interaction flows as parts of omni-channel solutions delivered based on user needs and clients' requirements;
- Closely collaborated with design researchers, visual designers, and business strategists on field studies, client visits, and client workshops.

EDUCATION

University of Minnesota

Ph.D. in HCI (Computer Science) Aug 2017 – Aug 2022

University of Washington

Master in HCI+D Sept 2014 – Aug 2015

St. Olaf College

B.A. Computer Science and Math Sept 2010 – May 2014

SKILLS

Platforms & Tools Adobe Creative Suite

Axure
Figma / Sketch
Google Analytics
InVision
JIRA / Trello
Qualtrics / SurveyMonkey
Node.js / React
Unity / UE

Design

Digital Fabrication Information Architecture Prototyping (Low-High Fidelity) Storyboarding Wireframing

User Research A/B Testing

Contextual Inquiry
Diary Studies
Experiment Design
Focus Group
Heuristic Evaluation
Interview
Journey Mapping
Log Analysis
Participatory Design
Survey
Usability Testing

Programming Languages

C/C++
HTML&CSS
Java
JavaScript
Processing / p5.js
Python
R
SQL